<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathematics on Entropic Legos</title>
    <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/tags/mathematics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mathematics on Entropic Legos</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 22:05:59 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/tags/mathematics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A (Wannabe) Topologist&#39;s Apology - Let&#39;s Bake a Cake!</title>
      <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/topo-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 22:05:59 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/topo-cake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;gen-topology-brig-connection-maj-manifold&#34;&gt;Gen. Topology, Brig. Connection, Maj. Manifold&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first issue you run into when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to learn topology and differential geometry, if you&amp;rsquo;ve never taken a class in &amp;ldquo;advanced&amp;rdquo; maths before, is the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s studded with definitions, often with no clear motivation. Now of course this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case when these ideas were being worked out, they just didn&amp;rsquo;t make things up as they pleased. In this series of articles, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a step back from rigorous mathematics and try to come up with intuitive notions that best convey these ideas. Today we&amp;rsquo;ll give a big picture overview of topologies, manifolds, and connections. Intended audience includes those who&amp;rsquo;ve already had some exposure to these but can&amp;rsquo;t quite internalise the ideas and tie them together with a concrete example. If you have no idea at all about any of these things, you might still try reading, but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t encourage you to, at least before you&amp;rsquo;ve had some proper exposure from any book or lecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Castles in the Air: How Econ 101 Butchers Math - Part 1 </title>
      <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/symmetry-econ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 16:48:41 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/symmetry-econ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-symmetry-to-expose-the-fraud-poster-child-of-economics&#34;&gt;Using Symmetry to Expose the Fraud Poster Child of Economics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whenever we hear of the term &amp;ldquo;economics&amp;rdquo;, the first picture that comes to mind is that of money. The second picture, if you&amp;rsquo;ve been put through at least some sort of formal economic education as in high schools, is the famous supply-and-demand curves. They&amp;rsquo;re the ubiquitous poster-child of the field of economics, the same as $E = mc^2$ or the apocryphal &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;apple falling on Sir Isaac&amp;rsquo;s head&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; in the field of physics. Despite the provocative title, I know and appreciate these models within their scope of usage, and the intent of this essay remains more mathematical than economical. As a noneconomist, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know how much they&amp;rsquo;re used in advanced economic work, but in public discourse of economic policymaking, they have proven so far to be invaluable assets, shedding light on everything starting from local egg prices and the exchange rates in a forex market to economic policymaking on a global level. Yet its mathematical underpinnings seem woefully underexplored. This essay will be an outsider&amp;rsquo;s journey into attempting to formalize the immensely influential yet rather nebulous hand-wavy tools. The goal is, at the very least, to serve as a good demo of how simple mathematical principles and &amp;ldquo;gut feelings&amp;rdquo;, pursued with determination, can lead to delightfully pleasant results. My starting point into the attack will be to a simple and seemingly reasonable hypothesis: &lt;em&gt;the supply curve can be viewed as a demand curve for money from the seller&amp;rsquo;s perspective&lt;/em&gt;. But first, let&amp;rsquo;s review a bit about the classical model and see where it shines rather dazzlingly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
