<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ontology on Entropic Legos</title>
    <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/tags/ontology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ontology on Entropic Legos</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 23:42:32 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/tags/ontology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy of Religion by Murray and Rea First Thoughts: Chapter 1 - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/cambridge-philosophy-of-religion-c1p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 23:42:32 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/cambridge-philosophy-of-religion-c1p1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;god-epistemology-and-ontology&#34;&gt;God: Epistemology and Ontology&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following includes my first thoughts while reading &lt;em&gt;An Introduction to the Philosophy of Religion&lt;/em&gt; by Murray and Rea, largely unfiltered. This is the first part of my collected thoughts on chapter 1, in which rather than discussing directly what has been talked about in the chapter itself, I have written down my perspectives on how to go about solving the epistemological and metaphysical problems associated with the question of God. In the next part, in shaa Allah, I will write about what exactly has been discussed in the chapter and how that fits (or does not) with my framework captured below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everywhere Yet Nowhere: The Ontological Status of Energy</title>
      <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/energy-ontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 18:37:18 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/energy-ontology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;energy-is-everywhere-or-is-it&#34;&gt;Energy is Everywhere. Or Is It?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We love energy. Our civilisation is built on energy. Each phase in the history of the human civilisation is marked by inventing some radically more efficient way to extract energy from some &amp;ldquo;stored form&amp;rdquo;. From eating fruits and veggies storing energy obtained from the sun to burning the carcasses of them to smashing subatomic particles off of each other, we&amp;rsquo;ve certainly come a long way. We can extract energy &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo; in even the remotest corner of the smallest conceivable energy storage - an atom. And with all this energy we power our homes, our offices, our factories, and most importantly, our electronic appliances, including the one we&amp;rsquo;re reading/writing this post on. But &lt;em&gt;what exactly&lt;/em&gt; is energy?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
