<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathematical Modelling on Entropic Legos</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/entropic-legos/tags/mathematical-modelling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mathematical Modelling on Entropic Legos</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:05:02 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/entropic-legos/tags/mathematical-modelling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Economic Modelling Done Right - Transactional Invariance In Action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entropic-legos/posts/symmetry-econ-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:05:02 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entropic-legos/posts/symmetry-econ-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a post several months back, I discussed how the traditional straight-line supply and demand models are limited in their scope. On the basis of symmetry considerations between money and goods, I came up with &amp;ldquo;chart transition maps&amp;rdquo;, so to speak, for going back and forth between a money-space representation of transactions and a goods-space representation. The classical supply-curve thus transformed into a money-space demand curve was a dud, leading me to rejecting the status quo. The &lt;em&gt;transactional invariance transformations&lt;/em&gt; coupled with judiciously considered applications of what I call the &lt;em&gt;principle of transactional symmetry&lt;/em&gt; plus other reasonable assumptions about supply-and-demand behaviour yield different classes of mathematically plausible supply-demand scenarios corresponding to different physical situations. In this post I discuss a few examples of coming up with a few such solution classes from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Castles in the Air: How Econ 101 Butchers Math - Part 1 </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/entropic-legos/posts/symmetry-econ/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 16:48:41 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/entropic-legos/posts/symmetry-econ/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;supply-and-demand-curves-are-a-scam&#34;&gt;Supply and Demand Curves Are a Scam&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I know, I know. I sound like a crackpot theorist from the title. But hear me out for a sec. It&amp;rsquo;s deeper than you think. Here&amp;rsquo;s a taste of what&amp;rsquo;s to come: supply and demand curves should be preserved under some transformations if they are to behave symmetrically, but they aren&amp;rsquo;t. Why should you care though? IDK, since supply and demand curves &amp;ldquo;determine&amp;rdquo; prices, and if the curves aren&amp;rsquo;t sufficiently well-defined we may have no notion of &amp;ldquo;eqilibrium price&amp;rdquo; or no single &amp;ldquo;equilibrium price&amp;rdquo; and so on?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
