<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Entropic Legos</title>
    <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Entropic Legos</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 23:42:32 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy of Religion by Murray and Rea First Thoughts: Chapter 1 - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/cambridge-philosophy-of-religion-c1p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 23:42:32 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/cambridge-philosophy-of-religion-c1p1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;god-epistemology-and-ontology&#34;&gt;God: Epistemology and Ontology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following includes my first thoughts while reading &lt;em&gt;An Introduction to the Philosophy of Religion&lt;/em&gt; by Murray and Rea, largely unfiltered. This is the first part of my collected thoughts on chapter 1, in which rather than discussing directly what has been talked about in the chapter itself, I have written down my perspectives on how to go about solving the epistemological and metaphysical problems associated with the question of God. In the next part, in shaa Allah, I will write about what exactly has been discussed in the chapter and how that fits (or does not) with my framework captured below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everywhere Yet Nowhere: The Ontological Status of Energy</title>
      <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/energy-ontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 18:37:18 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/energy-ontology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;energy-is-everywhere-or-is-it&#34;&gt;Energy is Everywhere. Or Is It?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We love energy. Our civilisation is built on energy. Each phase in the history of the human civilisation is marked by inventing some radically more efficient way to extract energy from some &amp;ldquo;stored form&amp;rdquo;. From eating fruits and veggies storing energy obtained from the sun to burning the carcasses of them to smashing subatomic particles off of each other, we&amp;rsquo;ve certainly come a long way. We can extract energy &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo; in even the remotest corner of the smallest conceivable energy storage - an atom. And with all this energy we power our homes, our offices, our factories, and most importantly, our electronic appliances, including the one we&amp;rsquo;re reading/writing this post on. But &lt;em&gt;what exactly&lt;/em&gt; is energy?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind Theory Update</title>
      <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/mind-theory-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 23:40:49 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/mind-theory-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-consciousness-conundrum&#34;&gt;The Consciousness Conundrum&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been gone from the blog for months. In the meantime, my country has witnessed a successful overthrowing of a tyrant called Sheikh Hasina, among other things. The last time I posted it was about &lt;em&gt;the Zig programming language&lt;/em&gt; and about &lt;em&gt;Plato&amp;rsquo;s Republic&lt;/em&gt;. Because I have the attention span of a little child, I&amp;rsquo;ve obviously still &lt;em&gt;not finished&lt;/em&gt; learning Zig, nor have I finished going through &lt;em&gt;The Republic&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been bouncing from one interest to another like a pinball in a pinball machine - from working with Arduino and ESP32 to building raw logic gates with transistors on a breadboard, from Plato to Wittgenstein, from Hodgkin-Huxley to Hopfield, and from graph theory to category theory - I&amp;rsquo;ve been exploring quite a vast terrain over these past months. And as rare as this may be, I for the first time in my life feel that I&amp;rsquo;m finding a common thread running through all my interests. And it&amp;rsquo;s the consciousness conundrum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Plato&#39;s Republic</title>
      <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/republic-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 15:13:44 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/republic-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-platos-republic---e1&#34;&gt;Understanding Plato&amp;rsquo;s Republic - E1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This the first episode in (hopefully) a series of several articles where I narrate my own understanding of &lt;em&gt;The Republic&lt;/em&gt;, the magnum opus of &lt;em&gt;Plato&lt;/em&gt;. In this episode, I discuss about the very initial parts of chapter 1 of the book. I give an overview of what transpires before Thrasymachus (while Socrates&amp;rsquo; dialogues contain a lot of different characters much like a play, the exact names of them are not so important to take note of except for a few prominent figures that play a crucial role in Socrates&amp;rsquo; arguments), the most vocal and prominent interlocutor of Socrates in chapter 1, starts engaging with Socrates. (This covers up to page 14 of the &lt;em&gt;Penguin Classics&lt;/em&gt; translation.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
