<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Relativity on Entropic Legos</title>
    <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/tags/relativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Relativity on Entropic Legos</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 19:39:25 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/tags/relativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ontological Status of Time - Preliminary Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/time-prelim/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 19:39:25 +0600</pubDate><author>hugo@example.com (Entropic Legos)</author>
      <guid>https://susmit31.github.io/entropic-legos/posts/time-prelim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-clock&#34;&gt;What is a Clock?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A philosopher and a physicist walk into a cafe. The philosopher asks the physicist to define &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo;. The physicist says,&amp;ldquo;simple - &lt;em&gt;that which is measured by a clock&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Cool, but &lt;em&gt;what is a frickin clock?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, replies the exasperated philosopher. (The real fun, however, happens when both of them are the same person.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This post is not to discuss my thoughts on time in an elaborate manner. I&amp;rsquo;ll defer that to a later time when I feel that my ideas have reached their ultimate form. But for now, I&amp;rsquo;d like to drop some hints. I&amp;rsquo;m, for the time being (pun intended and very much apt), a presentist. If I find at some point that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit the data, I&amp;rsquo;ll drop it with no ifs and buts. I just want to see which hypothesis works better. The time hypothesis doesn&amp;rsquo;t, as I want to make plausible in what follows. &lt;strong&gt;This post argues that time is not fundamental but an emergent property of change and memory. I sketch how presentism could survive relativity, reinterpret GR, and set the stage for a future quantum theory.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
